ARAM PODOLSKI

PROFILE

I am a software engineer based in Denver, Colorado. I am comfortable full-stack and with all things AWS. I am the co-creator of Haven, a centralized secrets manager for small teams. Previously, I worked as a flight software engineer for the Orion space program.

EXPERIENCE

2020 - present

Haven, Co-Creator, Software Engineer

haven-secrets.github.io ∂

- Co-created open-source secrets manager using AWS, Node.js, Express and React/Redux.
- Implemented secrets storage in AWS using DynamoDB to minimize latency.
- Resolved issue of temporary credentials by utilizing AWS Lambda to enforce one hour limit for new user creation.
- Utilized AWS CloudFormation to ensure architecture is set up and torn down in a repeatable manner.
- Set up AWS IAM permissions to restrict access to AWS KMS master key and secrets on a per project and environment basis.
- Designed solution utilizing AWS Encryption SDK to perform envelope encryption of application secrets.
- Designed user-friendly UI in React and CLI to allow users to easily centralize their secrets.
- Published multiple NPM packages for Haven.
- Co-authored technical case study: https://haven-secrets.github.io/case-study ≥

2020 - present

Self-Employed, Full-stack Web Developer

Built large number of full-stack web applications including:

- A React web application that allows for viewing and filtering of airline routes.
- A ticket tracking application built using Ruby/Rails and PostgreSQL.
- A Trello-like application with Rails REST API back-end and React/Redux front-end.

2014 - 2020

ISYS Technologies, Software Engineer, Senior Software Engineer

- Worked on the flight software team for the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle. Duties included software preliminary design, detailed design, coding, testing, integration, verification and build management.
- Developed mission critical software to route commands from the Crew Module to appropriate component on European Service Module for Artmeis I.
- Updated software and documentation based on feedback from NASA stakeholders.

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

B.S. Aerospace Engineering, University of Colorado at Boulder

SKILLS

Back End

Node.js, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, Express, RESTful APIs

Front End

Javascript(ES6), React, Redux, CSS, HTML

Cloud(AWS)

SDK, Lambda, KMS, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM

Other

Git, Perforce, Jira, Scrum, Agile, Confluence, Crucible, C++